Sanjeev Kumar

Delhi. India



k96sanjeev@gmail.com



8797155839



linkedin.com/in/kumar-sanju

Summary

I am a Java Developer with 2 years of experience, working in the information technology and service industry. I am extremely passionate about my work and always looking for an opportunity to grow. I specialize in Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, Jersey RESTful Web Services. I have also experience in Apache Kafka, MongoDB, and know Amazon Web Services.

Experience

Software Engineer

TO THE NEW

Aug 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months +)

As a Backend Developer(Java), I worked on-

- 1. Netcore Email and SMS service integration.
- 2. Integration and Maintenance of Techprocess and RazorPay payment gateway.
- 3. Integration of 3rd party APIs and create microservices with OSGi configuration.
- 4. Understanding requirements and creating the Business Rules Management System using Drools.
- 5. PDF generation using Apache PDFBox and iText.
- 6. Integration of FTP file system.
- 7. Database schema designing and integration.
- 8. Jersey RESTful Web Services and Jenkins

™ Trainee

TO THE NEW

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019 (6 months)

As a Java trainee, I worked on-

- 1) Apache Kafka.
- 2) Restful Web Services with Spring Framework.
- 3) Gradle and Maven build tools.
- 4) SQL and NoSql databases.
- 5) Grails and Groovy.
- 6) Git and Jira.
- 7) Others- Javascript, Ajax, Thymeleaf, Jmeter, Load testing, Jenkins

Education



Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Master of Computer Applications, Computer Science 2016 - 2019

Ranchi University

Bachelor of Computer Application, Computer Science 2013 - 2016

Bihar School Examination Board(BSEB)

Intermediate, Science 2011 - 2013

Central Board of Secondary Education
Schooling

Licenses & Certifications

- (1) Python(Basic) HackerRank Campus Club, AUFS
- Master MongoDB, the NOSQL leader with Clarity and Confidence Udemy
- RESTful Web Services with Spring Framework Udemy
- AWS Technical Professional (Digital) Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- AWS Business Professional (Digital) Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Google Analytics for Beginners Google Analytics Academy Issued Aug 2019 Expires Jul 2022
- React The Complete Guide Udemy

Skills

Java • Spring Framework • MySQL • MongoDB • Linux • GitHub • IntelliJ IDEA • Hibernate • Debugging • Project Coordination

Honors & Awards

Star Performer - TO THE NEW

Dec 2020

Recognized as Star Performer and being rewarded in the AEM BU Meet held on December 24, 2020.